

Anders Lykkegaard

IT-Product Developer

% +45 42 17 74 90

Anders_lykkegaard@hotmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/anders-lykkegaard

Profil-

With a master's in IT-product development, I have developed a skillset combining computer science and design, which enables me to be responsible for different roles in a team within a development project. This means I can function as the link between UX designers and developers or be in both roles. Additionally, these skills allow me to be a part of the entire process from generating ideas to implementation and test of IT-systems.

My motivation and main competencies are developing new and innovative IT-solutions, problem solving, and design systems which are tailored to the users, so they will have an awesome experience.

Personally, I can acquire new knowledge fast, because I used to investigate which technology would fit a project, and learn how to use it afterwards.

Education-

M.Sc. - IT-Product Development

2016-2018

Department of Computer Science at Aarhus University
I am specialized in three areas:

• IT-Product Development: Shape Changing Interfaces, Interactive Spac-

es, Urban Intervention, and Innovation Project.

- **Advanced Pervasive Computing**: Pervasive Positioning, Context Awareness, and Augmented Reality.
- **Human-Computer Interaction**: Theories and Qualitative Methods in HCl, User Experience, and Social and Collaborative Computing.

These courses are a combination of product development, HCI, and computer science. The it product development courses have assisted me in thinking creatively, the HCI courses give me a strong methodical foundation to understand users and analyze IT-systems, and with the knowledge acquired from computer science courses, I can develop IT-systems.

-Work Experience

Service Assistance at OUH 2014-2016

Vacation job at Odense University Hospital. I had the responsibility for a ward and some of my responsibilities were: ensuring that the patients had a good experience, and cleaning. Furthermore, I learned to work with many different professions (doctors, nurses, etc.) and deliver good service.

Disabled Career

2012-2013

I helped with everyday challenges such as: grocery shopping, weekend trips, personal care, and be at the disposal for the person. I have aquired skills within: responsibility, open-minded, and it has developed me personally.

Language

- Dansih, native language
- English, fluent

My master's program in English and I have spent a semester at University of Queensland (Australia), which means I speak and write English fluently. Furthermore, my master's thesis and thesis defense were conducted in English.

Semester at University of Queensland, Australia

2017

I enrolled in the following courses: Data Mining, Digital Prototyping, Introduction to Management, and Data Analytics and Information Management.

BSc - IT

2013-2016

Department of Computer Science at Aarhus University

Fundamental computer science courses (software development, algorithms, and HCI) combined with design (physical design, UX, user-centered design, and interaction design).

An example of the above competencies is my bachelor project. We investigated how we could improve parents' with small children's sleep using smartwatch sensors. We had three iterations in the development process, where we used methods such as interviews, online surveys, usability test, and UX evaluation to constantly improve our prototype. One of our discoveries was the potential for waking one parent up instead of two using vibration.

Publications-

PeaceKeeper

2016

My group and I published a scientific article and demonstrated it at the Augmented Human conference in Geneva. Our project treated sound challenges at old dormitories and we developed a prototype where you anonymously and discreetly could make your neighbor aware of the noise the person is making.

The article can be found on this link:

https://pure.au.dk/ws/files/108943860/PeaceKeeper CameraReady.pdf.

In addition to the article, we did a presentation for Datalogforeningen where we shared our experience from having a project to publishing and presenting the final article.

Skills-

Technical Experience

- lava
- Em-Unity bedded (C#) systems
- Vuforia (loT)
- Android Arduino
- **Firebase** (C/C++)

Design Programs

- **Photoshop**
- **InDesign**
- Illustrator

Knowledge About

- **HTML**
- CSS (Bootstrap)

-Voluntary Work-

Board member

2016-Now

I love badminton which is why I am a board member for my badminton club in Aarhus. As a board member, I am responsible for making decisions that ensure the wellbeing of the club now and in the future. Furthermore, I create social events, negotiate contracts, and oversee IT where I have set up and maintain our website:

www.akademisk-badminton.dk.

Tutor at Aarhus University

2014-2016

I have been a tutor for two years where I planned and made sure of a good orientation week for new students. After orientation week I followed them for six months, where I help them if they had problems, answered questions, and helped to secure a good start for them. Additionally, I was selected as coordinator for a small team to ensure up-to-date material for the new students.

-About Me-

When I have spare time, I usually spend time with my girlfriend and friends. Often, we play board games (also advanced ones) and enjoy a nice beer. Additionally, I have a big passion for all kinds of technologies such as electronics, sensors, and Arduinos which I like to build small projects from.